Guide to the Stanford University, Humanities Honors Program, Theses
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Theses, pre-1990
  - Rogers, Kathleen, Picasso: a creative consciousness in relation to tradition., 1954 (Box 16)
  - Rovin, Lisa, Quentin Compson's struggles with history in Faulkner's Absalom, Absalom., 1979 (Box 16)
  - Rubenstein, James Louis, Desire and the imagination: William Wordsworth and Wallace Stevens., 1985 (Box 23)
  - Rusk, Laurie, symbolism and the poetic imagination in the works of Baudelaire and Wallace Stevens., 1976 (Box 6)
  - Salter, Lucille A., Profile of Post Modern Man., 1964 (Box 16)
  - Samuels, Bruce, R. D. Laing's theory of Schizophrenia: psychology, philosophy, and literature., 1984 (Box 23)
  - Sanders, Jane, The Edge of Life., 1959 (Box 16)
  - Sanders, Robert Greene, The social responsibility of the artist: the aesthetic theories of William Morris and Walter Gropius., 1974 (Box 16)
  - Sanford, Robert, The last works of Henri Matisse: their stylistic develpment and their appropriateness to a religious context in the Chapel of the Rosary at Venice., 1971 (Box 16)
  - Sauer, Jo A., Philip Melanchton: the reformer as humanist., 1975 (Box 16)
  - Sayre, Henry, The American intellectual and his politics since World War II. (Box 17)
  - Schein, Elizabeth, The Author's Manipulation of the Reader in "La Divinia Commedia" and "Paradise Lost."., 1981 (Box 17)
  - Schiff, Benjamin, Nietzsche: A Unique Critique of Moral Values., 1979 (Box 17)
  - Schimke, Faith, Sigmund Freud: His personality and his Theories on Religion., 1954 (Box 17)
  - Scholtz, Gretchen, The Primitive Element in Rousseau, Gaugin, and Van Gogh., 1957 (Box 17)
  - Schor, Judith, Three Spanish Writers in Exile., 1980 (Box 17)
  - Scofield, Sharon, An introductory study of the relationship of Christianity to the dance., 1967 (Box 17)
  - Scott, Charity, "In tempo d'uno, in spazio d'uno": an introduction to the world of Eugenio Montale.., Spring 1973 (Box 17)
  - Scott, William David, Richard Wagner: Theorist of the Music-Drama., 1956 (Box 17)
  - Seed, Marie Suzanne, John Fowles: four novels., 1975 (Box 17)
  - Seeley, Constance, Albert Schweitzer--A Creative Flame.. (Box 17)
  - Seley, Nan M., The origins and development of the cult of the Virgin Mary in Egypt., Spring 1973 (Box 17)
  - Seward, Paul, Man in Conflict, and Man Absurd., 1964 (Box 17)
  - Shannon, R.S., Tradition, Disease, Eros, and Death in the Symbolism of the "The Magic Mountain..."., 1966 (Box 17)
  - Shenker, Arden E., The Development of a Roman Legal Ethic., 1959 (Box 17)
  - Shepherd, Prudence., Alienation and ideology: The ideas of Daniel Bell, 1936-1960., 1978 (Box 17)
  - Sherry, Christine Elizabeth, Literary expressions of Mexican cultural nationalism., 1976 (Box 17)
  - Shilts, John A., A Thousand and One Nights: An Essay on Remembrance of Things Past., 1966 (Box 17)
  - Shookhoff, David W., The Valley and the Waterers: An Archetypal Approach to the Plays of Bertolt Brecht., 1966 (Box 17)
  - Shorrock, Mary, My Lord Halifax - A Study of Restoration England., 1953 (Box 17)
  - Shurtleff, Bill, Michelangelo's major sculptures: analysis and interpretation., 1963 (Box 17)
  - Siegel, Michael J., Nietzsche and the Wagnerian Experience., 1983 (Box 23)
  - Simonson, Delberta, Donne in the Twentieth Century., 1960 (Box 17)
  - Sims, Jeffrey, Physicians of Modern Culture: Civilization and Instinct in Nietzsche and Freud., May 17, 1985 (Box 23)
  - Sinha, Gita Ajali, Rasa Realization: Spiritual vs. Non-Spiritual Interpretations of Indian Aesthetic Pleasure., 1995 (Box 17)
  - Skouras, Damaris, Savage Thought: An aesthetic of the mind., 1978 (Box 17)
  - Slovic, Steve, Goethe in English: Thought on the Making of a Bibliography., May 24, 1984. (Box 23)
  - Smith, Diana, Dream and Reality in the United Nations Architecture., 1959 (Box 17)
  - Smith, Edwin R., Beauty: a comment on the feminine., 1975 (Box 17)
  - Smith, Eric H., Themes and Problems in Schleiermacher's "The Christian Faith"., 1964 (Box 17)
  - Smith, John Franklin Sandy, Dietrich Bonhoffer, th individual and the community: a textual explication of Bonhoeffer's writings relating his Christology to his Ecclesiology., 1978 (Box 17)
  - Snell, David C., A study of Ugaritic and Israelite legal Texts., 1970 (Box 18)
  - Soderberg, John, Samuel Beckett's Art of Reduction., 1981 (Box 18)
  - Solomon, Louise M., An Existential Reading of Charlotte Bronte's "Villete"., June 1985 (Box 23)
  - Solomonson, Katherine., Saint-Denis and Chartres, the gothic cathedral and the divine right of kings., 1978 (Box 18)
  - Solow, Katherine, Conflict and Chaos: an analysis of the works of Tom Stoppard., undated (Box 18)
  - Soyster, Matthew, Dostoevsky and Ibsen: A Renaissance of tragedy., 1975 (Box 18)
  - Spears, Jay, The artist as politician: a study of the political involvements and socio-historical theories of W.B. Yeats., 1971 (Box 18)
  - Spelman, Jennie, Italian Futurism and its Relation to Fascism: A Case Study of Totalitarianism in Art and Politics., May 1, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Sperberg, Christopher Michael, Approaching "Mother Courage" or Who's Afraid of Betrolt B., 1979 (Box 18)
  - Sprague, Rick, The entrance way: the Early Dialectics Within Husserl's Transcendental Phenomology., 1968 (Box 18)
  - Spritzer, David, Limitations on Ancient Israelite Monarchy., 1962 (Box 18)
  - Stanger, R. Jonathon, Chretien's "Yvain": The construction of Romance from Reality., 1974 (Box 18)
  - Starr, Peter T., The sign and society: Literary Responsibility in three early writings of Roland Barthes., 1978 (Box 18)
  - Starr, Philip D., The Oblong Blur., 1966 (Box 18)
  - Stauffer, Robert A., Existntial or Personalistic Psychotherapy as it Relates to Psychosomatic Medicine., 1970 (Box 18)
  - Steinhardt, Sam, The Nature of Man in Martin Buber's "I and Thou"., 1979 (Box 18)
  - Stephene, Scott E., Lawrence and James: "The one and the many"., Spring 1973 (Box 18)
  - Sterling, Bess Lauretta, The Noh Drama of Japan: The Creation and Appreciation of the Arts as a Means to Enlightenment., Spring 1973 (Box 18)
  - Sterling, Dorothy, The Personality of Henry Adams., 1953 (Box 18)
  - Stevenson, David, A Criticism of Sartre's Concept of the Other: Prolegomna to th Phenomonenology of Love., 1971 (Box 18)
  - Stewart, Lynn, From Mediator to Magistrate: The Development of the Roman Judge., 1981 (Box 18)
  - Stillwell, Suzanne M., Napolean Bonaparte: A Man Without a Country., 1966 (Box 18)
  - Stiver, Charles E. Jr., An Examination of Camus' Ethical Philosophy., 1971 (Box 18)
  - Stokes, Lynne Ruelaine, The Electra Theme., 1966 (Box 18)
  - Streeter, Deborah, Joan of Arc: An Analysis of her Progression from Witch to Saint., Spring 1973 (Box 18)
  - Stroud, David G., The Scientific Attitude and Totalitarian State., 1965 (Box 18)
  - Stuart, Robert Lee, Baron Von Hugel and the Essential Tensions of the Christian Life., 1959 (Box 18)
  - Sullens, Idelle, The New Opera Synthesis., August 20, 1943 (Box 18)
  - Suzawa, Valerie M., Dickens and the World of Criminality., 1989 (Box 18)
  - Talbot, Alan, Voices and Answers: A Fugal Study of "Doctor Faustus"., 1980 (Box 18)
  - Taylor, Alan D., Eschatology and the Problems of Finitude and Sin: A Theological and Non-Theological Approach. (Box 18)
  - Taylor, Karen J., The Ethical Visions of Three Italian Renaissance Gentlemen: Malleo Palmieri, Buldassare Casiglione and Giovanni Della Casa., Spring 1973 (Box 19)
  - Taylor, Roberta, The Outsider and Mass Society., 1958 (Box 19)
  - Theimann, Michael, Mystical Influence on the Formulation of the Theory of Early Modern Abstract Art., 1979 (Box 19)
  - Thomas, James, Public Reaction to the House Commite on Un-Americen Activities., 1954 (Box 19)
  - Thompson, Robert, Reason and Liberty: Freedom...Kant and Hegel., 1965 (Box 19)
  - Tilley, James, Kierkegaard and Jund: The Concept of the Self., 1978 (Box 19)
  - Timbie, Janet, The Theory of the Abolition of Time Applied to Poynesia: A Comparison of Modern and Primitve Man., 1970 (Box 19)
  - Timmins, Paul V., The Denver Charter Convention of 1903: A Fight for Democracy., 1984 (Box 23)
  - Tostevin, Nancy, The Challenge to Modern American Tragedy., 1961 (Box 19)
  - Treadgold, Laura, Matteo Ricci: an apostolic policy of accomodation., 1978 (Box 19)
  - Trinkaus, Linda, Indirect communication in the writings of Soren Kierkegaard., 1968 (Box 19)
  - Trumball, Margaret, Three women: Elsa Morante, Natalia Ginzburg, Dacia Mariani., 1975 (Box 19)
  - Tull, Alan C., Existentialism and Thomism., 1955 (Box 19)
  - Ungar, Barbara, Haiku in English Stanford Honors Essays in Humanities No. XXI., 1978 (Box 19)
  - Van Nest, Robert A., Essays on the Poetry of Rimbaud., Spring 1973 (Box 19)
  - Vaugh, Sharman, In Search of America., 1956 (Box 19)
  - Velarde, Robert L., Vincent Van Gogh: The Lonely One., undated (Box 19)
  - Vellani, Maria, Gustav LeBon: The Role of the Irrational in the Crisis of Modern Society., 1985 (Box 23)
  - Wahrhaftig, Albert L., Modern Mexican Architecture: A reflection of the aspirations of the Mexican Revolution., 1957 (Box 19)
  - Walkover, Andrew, The dialectics of Eden., 1974 (Box 19)
  - Wallen, Jeffrey, Jean Genet: the poetics of betrayal., 1977 (Box 19)
  - Waller, Diane, Confrontation with decadence, an analysis of The Man without Qualities., 1977 (Box 19)
  - Walton, Nancy, The interaction of social context and imagery in Dickens' Bleak House., 1981 (Box 19)
  - Warne, Janice, The interaction of Tyche, Techne, and Daimon in three plays by Euripides., 1979 (Box 19)
  - Waters, Reba, Euripedes' Trojan Women: interpretation and production., 1967 (Box 19)
  - Watkins, Greg, Elective Affinities: a look at textured forces and forms of desire., June 7, 1985 (Box 23)
  - Waxman, Virginia L., City of artists., 1955 (Box 19)
  - Webb, Joyce, Utopia and the plight of modern humanism., 1959 (Box 19)
  - Weedin, Ken, "Myself am Hell.", 1962 (Box 19)
  - Weix, Gretchen Garnett, An analysis of gender symbolism in the mythic novel: The Sybil., August 1981 (Box 23)
  - Wennberg, John, The parable of Albert Schweitzer: his life and thought., 1956 (Box 19)
  - Wertheim, Jerry Todd, Races Condemned: politics in Nostromo and One Hundred Years of Solitude., May 17, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Wertheimer, Clay, In Search of Paradigms: An evaluation of Thomas S. Kuhn's and Paul Feterabend's description of science., 1980 (Box 19)
  - Wessner, Dan, The joy of C. S. Lewis., 1979 (Box 19)
  - West, Hugh, The Dangerous Guess: James Agee and the Romantic tradition. (Box 19)
  - Weston, Nancy Ann, A humanist theory of feminism: historical foundations in John Stuart Mill and Karl Marx., 1977 (Box 20)
  - Wheeler, Dennis, The Oceanic Feeling., 1959 (Box 20)
  - White, Harry L., The last supper of Leonardo Da Vinci., 1970-71 (Box 20)
  - White, Rolland B., The art of Pirandello., 1970 (Box 20)
  - White, William B., Ceasare Borgia and Machiavellianism., 1974 (Box 20)
  - Whittemore, Douglas McKinley, the concept of self in the philosophies of Kierkegaard and James., 1976 (Box 20)
  - Wiggin, Barbara Jane Moffitt, Discovering religion through Nikos Kazantzakis' The Odyssey: A Modern sequel., Spring 1973 (Box 20)
  - Wight, Edward D., Mission to the city. four views of the Protest Church in Urban America., 1969 (Box 20)
  - Wildman, Stephanie, "To be supremely human" A Study in John Barth., 1970 (Box 20)
  - Williams, Arnold, Philosophy and ideology: a study of Plato and Marx., 1978 (Box 20)
  - Williams, Harold, Situations in Greek tragedy., 1965 (Box 20)
  - Wilson, Suzanne, The intrusion of confusion: an inquiry into the problem of natural rights., 1950 (Box 20)
  - Wineman, Kathleen, Businessmen look at themselves: attitudes of Morgan, Carnegie, Rockefeller, and Ford., 1979 (Box 20)
  - Witt, Peter, the problem of moral choice and the effects of evil in Paradise Lost and Macbeth., 1978 (Box 20)
  - Wood, Brian Robert, A perspective of psychosomatic medicine in relation to ancient Greece., 1974 (Box 20)
  - Woodworth, Patrick, A portrait of three brothers., 1966 (Box 20)
  - Wos, Cheryl M., Color Symbolism in "Sir Gawain and the Green Knight"., 1968 (Box 20)
  - Wright, Elizabeth, Theology in the novels of Charles Williams., 1960 (Box 20)
  - Wrightman, Paul, Tightrope Balancing: The dialectics of Christian faith according to Kierkegaard., 1970 (Box 20)
  - Wyant, John R., The University and the State: a study of the academic in politics., Spring 1984 (Box 23)
  - Yerxa, Ron, The dissent of John Dos Passos., 1969 (Box 20)
  - Younger, Agnes, Utopia: heaven or hell?, 1956-57 (Box 20)
  - Zambrano, Mark A., Maira, Identity, and the colonization of Bra(s)il., 1981 (Box 20)
  - Zebouni, Maria S., Methodological Considerations., 1981 (Box 20)
  - Zweip, Joan, Anne Hutchinson and four New England historians., 1975 (Box 20)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-1990-179
  - Alexander, Stephanie M., Nietzche's model of the self., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Greta, A new name for woman: fiction and politics in the writing of Alice Walker and Monique Wittig., 1986 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Jason A., Alexander Solzhenitsyn's Reception in America: Review and analysis., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Baskin, Tina-Marie, What's so funny? The ideology of the female in American comic strips., 1986 (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Christina A., Creativity, Auto-therapy, and the "transcendent function": a Jungian reading of Virginia Woolf's To A Lighthouse., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Pamela, Women as Artists in three Novels by Virginia Woolf., 1986 (Box 1)
  - Canales, James E., Friendship's Value Revealed: The tension Between Romantic Love and Friendship in Four Shakespearean Plays., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Canton, James H., Soren and Kierkegaard on Suffering., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Capps, Lisa, From Silence to Serenity., 1986 (Box 1)
  - Claassen, Forrest, Truth beyond reason: an epistemological perspective on Karl Barth's early theology., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Cline, Lee K., Object and image: Nelson Goodman's theory of representation and the works of William Carlos Williams and Robert Rauschenberg., 1987 (Box 1)
  - Collins, R. Michael, The Jeffersonian moment: a soul for American political culture., 1987 (Box 1)
  - Cunningham, John C., Resurrection and recollection: the salvation of the temporally alienated self in Marcel Proust's Remembrance of Things Past., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Dickson, Mariah, Theodore Dreiser: realist or idealist?, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Doherty, Brigid, Theatrical painting/Painterly theatre: David Hockney and the Parade of Post-Modernism., 1987 (Box 1)
  - Durie, Daralyn, The virgin and the whore: the dichotomous nature of woman in Une Saison dans la Vie d'Emmanuel and Les Enfants du Sabbat., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Duyvestein, Janine G., The beautiful, the good and love in James Joyce's A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man and Ulysses: a study of applied Aquinas., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Eisner, Mark D., Marcel Duchamp and Robert Rauschenberg: an aesthetic of art and life., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Fischer, Scott K., Silent Antagonists: the autobiographies of Henry Adams and Andrew Carnegie., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Franklin, Sara Joan, Emily Bronte's Wuthering Heights and Robert Schumann's Piano Concerto in A Minor: A study of artistic expression"., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Gallagher, Catherine L., Freedom in Dostoevsky and Kundera., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Gerhauser, Lisa, The evolution of Calvinos' narrative discourse., 1986 (Box 1)
  - Gibson, Michael S., The structure of modernism: the works of Rilke and Le Corbusier., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Guest, Victoria, Reweaving the violated narrative: strategies for confronting the discourse of political terror in Luisa Valenzuela's The Lizard's Tail., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Gutierrez, Christine M., Thomas More's Utopia: Simplicity and Human Growth., 1987 (Box 1)
  - Hampton, Diana E., Lakota religious thought: a study of the seven rites in The Sacred Pipes., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Handley, George, Christopher Columbus and Prospero: Self-knowledge and the magic of books in a colonial world., 1989 (Box 2)
  - Handley, William, Virginia Woolf: the politics of narration., 1986 (Box 2)
  - Hansen, Wendy, Human conceptions and reality: people's misunderstandings of computer capabilitiess., 1986 (Box 2)
  - Harris, Wilmer J., Agape's three principles of justice: an examination of the societal implications of Christian love., 1986 (Box 2)
  - Hobson, Kathleen, "The Lonely Mind": An analysis of madness in Virginia Woolf's fiction., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Hutman, Theodore M., Aesthetic repetition and the creative temperament in Le Grand Meaulnes., 1986 (Box 2)
  - Illick, Christopher D., Bayonets and pitchforks: Looking for the relationship of politics to Literature in Homage to Catalonia and Animal Farm., 1989 (Box 2)
  - Israel, Melinda, Seeking the Phoenix: Artistic consciousness in the nuclear age., 1986 (Box 2)
  - Jackson, Shannon, A performance phenomenology: Problems of self, play, and character., 1989 (Box 2)
  - Jacobs, Marc D., New Science and Old Insights: the bio-philosophies of Edgar Morin and Immanuel Kant., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Jenkins, Jennifer, Dialectic and Development in Thomas Mann's The Magic Mountain., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Jenney, Anne W., Victory over the sun: a revolutionary opera's impact on Russian cubo-futurism., 1987 (Box 2)
  - Jolls, Christine, Towards an ideal deontology?: stripping down the subject in Kant and Rawls., 1989 (Box 2)
  - Kaschnitz, Ingrid von, The Bildungsreise of Wilhelm and Hans in Goethe's Wilhelm Meister and Mann's The Magic Mountain., 1986 (Box 2)
  - Kazanjian, David C., Deconstructions and reconstructions: history and subjectivity in Toni Morrison's Beloved and Christa Wolf's Patterns of Childhood., 1989 (Box 2)
  - Kotz, Elizabeth, Sexual identity and mythic history in Monique Wittig's Les Guerrilleres or, A handbook for active forgetting., 1986 (Box 2)
  - Kreger, Jennifer, The long rope: ethical issues in West Africa's health care., 1987 (Box 2)
  - Kwak, Yeong S., Philosophical and aesthetic perspectives on Chuang Tzu and Friedrich Nietzsche., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Larson, Laurie A., Liberation theology: two Latin American initiatives and two North American responses., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Lee, Edel C., The black female image in modern American advertising: from slavery to Virginia Slims., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Li, David, MacIntyre and moral education., 1986 (Box 2)
  - Lighty, Michael E., ideology and popular theatre in depression era America; the Federal Theatre Project, the Rise and Fall of social theatre., 1987 (Box 2)
  - Livinghouse, Don E., Echoes of Platonism and Neoplatonism from Kant to Valery., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Loschen, Christopher, Faust the existentialist: a study of Faustian characters in two plays of Jean-Paul Sartre., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Lowson, Charlotte C., The mystic heroine in the novels of Virginia Woolf., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Maitless, Noam C., The art of noise: the aesthetic environment of MTV., 1989 (Box 3)
  - McDonnell, John J., The Revolt against nihilism in the writings of Albert Camus., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Metzger, Sharon R., Catholicism and contraception: Where does the doctrine come from and why doesn't it work in the United States?., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Mills, Guy S., Epic distance diminished: from dreamplace to home in The Epic of Gilgamesh and The Odyssey., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Morehead, Kerstin, Lyrical impulses of the soul: William Carlos Williams' Kora in Hell., 1989 (Box 3)
  - Muftic, Theodore B., Ernest Hemingway and The Sun Also Rises: the psychology of a writer as an artist., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Muller, David C., The victimization of the reader in Book Four of Gulliver's Travels., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Patel, Neela, John Keats and the Reader., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Patrick, Stewart, Toward a systematic evolutionary view of human culture., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Perlman, Mace, Moliere and the Commedia dell'arte: improvisational illusion and the Angoisse of disillusionment., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Perret, George P., Necessity and contingency in Hegel's encyclopedia., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Poster, Vanessa, All My Children: A literary study of soap operas., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Randolph, Elizabeth B., Dialogics and gender: Re-speaking the female subject., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Rhinelander, Margaret T., Memory and critical perspective iin Christa Wolf's Kassandra., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Rosenthal, Michael, Frantz Fanon's concept of violence., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Rudolph, Marshall S., A critical examination of Adorno's essay: 'Alienated masterpiece: The Missa Solemis'., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Ryan, Pamela D., Mass Production and modernity: four American designers, 1920-1940., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Schaberg, David Copley, 'Literature and History Do Not Part Company': The Literary Nature of the Tso Chuan.., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Schechter, Anne, Impressionism and Phenomenology in Henry James' "The Turn of the Screw"., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Seinfeld, Keith S., Rorty, Conversation, and the Baggage of the West: A Literary Approach to Philosophy., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Silverman, Susan E., Time and the Problems of Self-Definition and Uncertainty: Proust, Beckett, and Stravinsky.., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Sorenson, Andrew L., Primo Levi: The Poetics of Remembrance., 1989 (Box 3)
  - Spiro, Joanna E., Henry James: From Economic Logic to Religious Reasoning.., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Stein, Barney, Reading and Writing a Notebook: Movements Toward Heteropia with Aime Cesaire's "Cahier d'un retour au paye natal."., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Stone, Hannah Cushing, Facets of Photography: Benjamin and Beyond., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Sungaila, Mary-Christine, "And the Mirror Crack'd...": Mirrorings and Masking in Merrill's "The Changing Light at Sandover."., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Suprenant, Katherine A., Struggle with Existential Limitations: A Study of Two Novels by D.H. Lawrence., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Thornton, Caroline M., Revelation by Reason: A Neo-Platonic Interpretation of Raphael's "School of Athens."., 1988 (Box 4)
  - Toledano, Gabrielle B., Francisco de Goya: "The Unliberal Imagination" and Personal Expressions of an 18th- and 19th-century "Modern" Artist., 1989 (Box 4)
  - Truitt, Allison J., The American Artist in Rome: A Study of Nathaniel Hawthorne's The Marble Faun and Henry James' Roderick Hudson., 1989 (Box 4)
  - Ungar, Lowell W., To Survive Whole: Oppression and Resistance in the Novels of Zora Neale Hurston and Alice Walker., 1987 (Box 4)
  - Ward, Jonathan K., From authority to freedom: innovative techniques used by Fowles and Hamilton., 1988 (Box 4)
  - White, Patricia (Patsy), Jane Austen and Mary Wollstonecraft: Women writers in a man's field., 1986 (Box 4)
  - Wichman, Heather, The fascination with Arthur., 1986 (Box 4)
  - Wilkins, Elizabeth A., Through the eyes of a child: a "neo-expressionist" view of postwar Italy., 1986 (Box 4)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-1992-165
  - Aitken, B. Scott, The uses of history in John Updike's Rabbit Trilogy., May 28, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Archer, Shirley J., In pursuit of the public interest: an analysis of the authorization and impact of the Motor Carriers Act of 1935., May 1981 (Box 1)
  - Arent, Shereen, A matter of priorities: reformist women's organizations' actions on welfare reform legislation and the implications for class bias in the women's movement., April 198- (Box 1)
  - Bailin, Paul Stuart, A word unspoken: Mystical language in Meister Eckhart., June 1991 (Box 1)
  - Balz, Chris, The mass sacrificial spectacle: The Doors in poetry and history., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Beaven, Simon W., Terrible Swift Sword: the action of grace in three stories by Flannery O'Connor., May 1991 (Box 1)
  - Bender, Claire E., Jules Roy: the conceptual other and the colonization of the female image in literature., January 1991 (Box 1)
  - Boderick, Michael, Plea-Bargaining in America: Why and Why So Much., 1979 (Box 1)
  - Bowers, Ann-Elise, The Pastoral Machine: Computers, Metaphors and American Culture., 1992 (Box 1)
  - Brandes, Carolyn P., "Let's Play a Gam:" Two Imaged of Succedd in the Life Board Games., 1991 (Box 1)